atollic.com 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy - Atollic - ST

##  ST WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY

ST is committed to protect the privacy of personally identifiable information collected from the web sites (including mobile web sites and apps) owned and controlled by STMicroelectronics International N.V. and STMicroelectronics N.V. affiliated companies (the “ST Sites”).

References to “we”, “our” or “us” in this Privacy Policy mean STMicroelectronics International N.V., a company incorporated under the laws of the Netherlands, having its registered offices at WTC Schiphol Airport, Schiphol boulevard 265, 1118 BH Luchthaven Schiphol, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, acting through its Swiss branch at 39, Chemin du Champ-des-Filles, CH-1228 Geneva – Plan-Les-Ouates, Switzerland (“ST”).

For the purposes of data protection laws, we are the “Data Controller” in respect of the personal data provided on the website www.st.com, on the extranet myST, on smarter.st.com, on blog.st.com and stmcu.com.cn.

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, store, use and disclose information, including your Personal Data (as defined hereafter), collected through ST Sites. By using ST Sites, you agree with ST's collection, use, storage and disclosure of your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made a part of ST Sites Terms of Use.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Data” is any information relating to an identified living person or a living person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by means reasonably likely to be used by ST, in particular by reference to an identification number, location data, online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that person.

###  3\. Personal Data We Collect

ST may collect, store and use various types of Personal Data, such as:

  * information about your computer, your visits and use of ST Sites (including IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths) and more generally information collected through cookies and similar technologies;
  * information provided when registering and completing profile details (such as, but not limited to, salutation, first and last name, email address, title or function, phone number, projects and employment or company details, country and other location details, category (e.g. journalist, investor etc. and industry);
  * your subscription choices for ST email notifications, alerts and/or newsletters;
  * information provided when using the services on ST Sites, or that is generated in the course of the use of those services (such as the timing, frequency and pattern of service use);
  * information relating to any purchases of goods and services, or any other transactions that you enter into through ST Sites (including name, address, contact details, email address and payment details);
  * information that you post on ST Sites (user name, profile pictures and the content of your posts);
  * information sent to ST through ST Sites or otherwise (including the communication content and metadata associated with the communication), e.g. when you contact us using the contact forms on the ST Sites;
  * information that you provide via our job search page to apply for open positions in ST; and
  * any other Personal Data communicated by you to ST.

Such Personal Data may be collected from:

  * you directly, when you use ST Sites, sign up for a newsletter, make a purchase, create a profile or use ST hardware/software products, attend a trade shows or events, or contact customer services;
  * a third-party, when you purchase or use third party services or products that utilize or distribute ST hardware/software products; or

  * other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, and social media platforms (e.g. for data such as company name, location, job title).

To the extent you submit any Personal Data about other people to ST, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit ST to use such third party Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

###  4\. Our use of your Personal Data

ST may use your Personal Data for the following purposes:

  * administer and personalise ST Sites and business for you by presenting products, marketing messages, commercial offers, and content tailored to you;
  * provide you with information, services made available by ST;
  * complete and fulfil purchases of products and services done through ST Sites or otherwise and execute transactions (send statements, process payments, orders, invoicing and overall manage your accounts);
  * send you non-marketing commercial communications;
  * share your Personal Data with other ST affiliates where appropriate to offer you a better service;
  * share your Personal Data with non-affiliated third parties such as distributor or business partners so that they contact you directly or complete and fulfil purchases of products and services done through ST Sites or otherwise;
  * send you email notifications that you have specifically requested, respond to your inquiries and fulfil your requests, such as to send you technical documents or whitepapers;
  * send you marketing communications relating to ST and selected third party businesses that ST believes may be of interest to you, such as newsletters, in accordance with your communication preferences (you can inform us at any time if you no longer wish to receive newsletter or marketing communications);
  * deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to any ST Sites;
  * perform data analysis, audits, crime/fraud monitoring and prevention, security, improving or modifying ST Sites;
  * identify usage trends, determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns, operating and expanding ST business activities;
  * associate information you provide us, with other information we collect from you or about you from third parties, for marketing and analytics purposes; and
  * check compliance with the terms and conditions governing the use of ST Sites.

Financial transactions are handled through ST payment services providers. You can review the providers’ privacy policies on their respective websites. ST will share information with ST payment services provider only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via ST Sites, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.

Your Personal Data are processed on the basis of at least one legitimate ground which may be, depending on the categories of Personal Data and the purposes of the processing: (i) your explicit consent (which may be withdrawn at any time), (ii) the performance of a contract with you or pre-contractual steps for a contract with you, (iii) compliance with our legal obligations or (iv) our legitimate interest (such as in running our business effectively and in improving the quality of our products and services) or the legitimate interest of the third parties to whom we transfer your Personal Data.

###  5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data to Third Parties

ST may share your Personal Data with its subsidiaries and any of ST’s employees, officers, insurers, professional advisers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors around the world for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. ST may also share your Personal Data with third-party suppliers and service providers worldwide for data processing, storage, and other services such as web site hosting, data analysis, order fulfillment and delivery, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, credit card and payment processing, auditing and other similar services.

More specifically, ST may need to share your Personal Data with third parties worldwide in order to deliver services or products requested by you in your country.

Furthermore ST may share your Personal Data with a third party worldwide in the event of any contemplated or actual reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of ST business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

ST will also share or release information, including Personal Data, if (i) ST has your permission to make the disclosure, (ii) when ST believes release is appropriate or required to comply with the applicable laws and/or to respond to requests from competent public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence, (iii) in connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings, (iv) enforce or apply ST Terms of Use and other policies or agreements, or (v) protect the rights, property or safety of ST and other users (including for fraud protection and credit risk reduction).

When you visit ST Sites, register for an online account with ST or enter or make purchases through ST Sites, subscribe to a newsletter, or enter a contest or other promotion, you may receive marketing communications from ST (subject to your consent, where applicable). If you receive these marketing communications, you may unsubscribe from those marketing communications at any time. Email messages will contain instructions on how to “unsubscribe” from receiving such marketing communications.

You are always free to update your communication preferences for the marketing activities performed by ST. Thus you may accept or refuse receiving marketing-related messages from ST in the future or update your communication preferences by following the instructions included in each marketing-related message.

ST shall comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please also note however that ST may still send you important administrative and transactional messages (i.e. service notifications) in connection with a transaction, your orders, updates or notifications about products you have purchased from ST, or information about your account.

###  7\. Retention of your Personal Data

ST will retain Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

ST will also retain Personal Data: (i) to the extent that ST is required to do so by law, or (ii) the Personal Data may be relevant to any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings, or (iii) in order to establish, exercise or defend ST’s rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk).

ST uses cookies and other tracking technologies online. Please read the ST Cookies Policy, which is part of this Privacy Policy, and is incorporated herein by reference Cookies Policy.

###  9\. Your Rights in Relation to your Personal Data

You have certain rights under applicable data privacy laws in relation to your Personal Data, including rights to, in certain circumstances:

  * request access to the Personal Data ST holds about you and be provided information in relation to that Personal Data (including the purposes for which it is processed, the recipients to whom that personal data has been or will be disclosed, how long it will be stored for, details of any automated decision-making and your right to lodge a complaint with a supervisor authority);
  * request that ST amends inaccurate Personal Data about you, and to have incomplete Personal Data completed;
  * request the erasure of the Personal Data ST holds about you, for example where it is no longer necessary for ST to hold the information;
  * object to or restrict ST’s processing of your Personal Data (including processing for direct marketing purposes). This includes the right to opt-out of receiving further marketing emails;
  * request that ST provides you with an electronic copy of the Personal Data we hold about you. To the extent it is technically feasible, ST can also transmit your Personal Data to another data controller;
  * object to any decision affecting you that has been taken solely by a computer or other automated process; and
  * contact the data protection supervisory authority of your country if you have any concern about the use of your Personal Data.

To exercise any of these rights, you may use the contact email address detailed in Section 17 of this Privacy Policy. ST will handle your request as soon as reasonably practicable, in accordance with applicable laws.

If any of the information that we hold about you in your myST Account is inaccurate or incomplete, you can also correct it through your myST Account.  If you have any questions about this or need help, inform us at:  [support.policies@st.com](mailto:support.policies@st.com).

ST may need to retain certain information for back-up and record-keeping purposes, as required under applicable legal obligations, and/or to complete any transactions that you agreed prior to requesting such change or deletion (e.g. when you make a purchase or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such purchase or promotion).

###  10\. International Transfers of Your Personal Data

ST may transfer your Personal Data to any ST group company worldwide when processing, storing and using information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. ST may also transfer Personal Data to its third party service providers located in a different country or territory to the one you are located in. ST may therefore transfer your Personal Data to territories outside the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) to countries which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the EEA, such as the United States of America, China, Singapore and India.

To the extent your Personal Data would be transferred to a country or territory outside the EEA that does not ensure an adequate level of protection for the rights and freedoms of data subjects in relation to the processing of Personal Data, we have in place requirements relating to such international data transfers. For example, where we transfer your information: (i) between ST affiliates, this is done pursuant to an agreement based on the EEA Data Export Contractual Clauses, and (ii) to third parties, we use specific contractual clauses designed to ensure those third parties respect the confidentiality of your personal data and use it only in connection with providing their services to use and in compliance with applicable data privacy laws.  If you would like further details, you can contact us by using the contact email address detailed in Section 17 of this Privacy Policy. Furthermore, Personal Data that you post or submit for publication on ST Sites may be available, via the internet, around the world. ST cannot prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.

###  11\. Security of Your Personal Data

ST pays attention to the security of your Personal Data, and therefore ST uses various security technologies to protect it, including secure servers, firewalls and encrypted solutions and reasonable and appropriate organizational, technical, and administrative measures to protect Personal Data within ST organization against unauthorized or unlawful access, alteration, disclosure or destruction.

However, transmissions over the internet are never entirely secure or error-free and ST does not guarantee the security of the information communicated to and/or from ST Sites. It is your responsibility to safeguard any password, user ID and other Personal Data while using ST Sites.

###  12\. Minors and children under the age of 13

The ST Sites are not directed at, and are not intended for minors and children under the age of thirteen (13). ST will not knowingly collect data from children without proper parental consent. If you believe that ST may have collected Personal Data from someone under the age of thirteen (13), or under the applicable age of consent in your country, without parental consent, you can contact ST to take appropriate measures to investigate and address the issue promptly. Parents wishing to access, review or delete their child’s Personal Data may contact ST by using the contact email address detailed in Section 17 of this Privacy Policy.

###  13\. Automated decision making

ST uses software to help us better understand how you like us to communicate with you and whether you may be interested in our products and services. For example, based on our records that you have recently shown interest in a certain product, our software helps us identify related products and services that may interest you. We may then use this to contact you about these.

ST may provide social computing tools to enable online sharing and collaboration among registered users. These include forums, wikis, blogs, instant messaging, open-source development and other social media platforms. When registering to use certain social computing tools on ST Sites, you may be asked to provide certain Personal Data. Such Personal Data and other information collected during the registration on ST Sites will be subject to this Privacy Policy, except Personal Data and other information that you make publicly available or you communicate to other participants. These tools may also include supplemental terms of use and may include additional privacy notices.

Any content or information (including Personal Data) that you post or make available to other participants on third party social media platforms is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies of those platforms and not subject to this Privacy Policy.

ST Sites may include hyperlinks to third party websites. ST has no control over such third party websites and their practices and is not responsible for the policies and practices of such third party websites. This Privacy Policy does not address the policies and practices of such third parties related to privacy and security, data collection, processing, use, storage, and disclosure of Personal Data.

###  16\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy supersedes all previous versions.

ST reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time.  Any change to this Privacy Policy will become effective when ST makes the revised Privacy Policy available on ST Sites or when ST notifies you of such change.

You can contact ST regarding this Privacy Policy at the following email address: [support.policies@st.com](mailto:support.policies@st.com).  Please provide ST with your contact details, the name of the ST Sites or service in question, and a detailed description of your request.

This policy was updated on May 22nd 2018.
